You can see, it really doesn't slow down at all.
OK, come on back over here. I'll get this our of our way.
Let's do a little wrap up. So, we were able to effectively reduce friction to essentially zero, and what happened?
[It never stopped.] [Well, it did stop but we stopped it.] We stopped it!
Do you think we could run this experiment in a way that if no one was there it would really go forever?
[I guess if you reduced friction all the way to zero.]
And removed the brick wall... [And removed the brick wall...] And removed the house next door.
[So you would have to have infinite space as well.]
It's really difficult to perform the ideal experiment and that's one of the things that makes motion a little difficult to understand.
This is an example of what is called Newton's First Law of Motion.
He said, back in 1687, that if an object is moving, if it's in motion, it will continue to move
in a straight line with a constant speed forever, unless acted upon by another force. In principle, that is true.
Scientists believe it is true. In practice you can never actually do that experiment. You can only think of the idealization of that experiment.
So that's one of the things that makes it a little difficult.