What do you think would happen if we could reduce friction even more?
[It would go even farther?] It would go even farther!
I like that answer! Sounds very logical!
If we push that to its logical conclusion, let's say we reduced friction even more after that, what happens?
[I guess if you could eventually get friction to zero the object would never stop.]
That's quite a statement!
[It makes me think of an episode of Magic School Bus I saw when I was a kid.
They shrunk down and that's what they talked about. If there was no friction (I think they were in an ice rink),
they said if there was no friction you could never stand still because you'd always be moving.]
Beautiful! So, believe it or not we can actually do that experiment.
Almost! We can make friction go to almost zero. I've got a special item to help us with that.
I have some dry ice. The beauty of dry ice (it's solid carbon dioxide) is that where regular ice melts into a liquid,
dry ice turns directly into a gas. We call that sublimation. So it doesn't make anything wet.
For our purposes, what's nice (see... that's the gas)
for our purposes when I put it on a smooth surface and rub it around to make the bottom flat
what'll happen is that it will float on a little cushion of gas.
So there won't be any rubbing between the dry ice and the floor, effectively removing friction.
It's not perfect, but it's very, very close.
So, why don't you get behind me.
I'm going to shove this the same way I was shoving the piece of wood and let's see how far it goes.
[Oh my gosh!] I mean, look at it! It's cruising! [Wow!]